LogMeIn Privacy Policy

Last Updated on December 31, 2019\*  
\*APEC Cross Border Privacy Rules System Statement Added on April 17, 2020

**Introduction**

This Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand (i) what information we collect from visitors to our websites or through our marketing channels. (ii) how we use such information at LogMeIn, and (iii) the choices you have associated with that information.

When we refer to “LogMeIn,” “we,” “our,” or “us” in this policy, we are referring to LogMeIn, Inc., and its subsidiaries and affiliates, as the “controller” (and/or a “business” under the CCPA) or the equivalent legal construct under applicable law of the information we process when you visit our websites and/or we interact with you through our marketing channels for business purposes. This Privacy Policy covers the digital properties listed here. When we refer to “personal information” in this policy, we are referring to personal data, personally identifiable information, or the equivalent of each under applicable law.

It is important to note that where LogMeIn handles personal information on behalf of or at the direction of its customers through their use of our Services, LogMeIn is the “processor” (and/or “service provider” under the CCPA) or the equivalent legal construct under applicable law of that data and LogMeIn’s use, processing, and handling of such data is done pursuant to the written instructions of its customers in the form of the Terms of Service, Data Processing Addendum, and/or any similar written agreement between the parties. In these cases, our use of information collected through our Service shall be limited to the purpose of providing and operating the Services for our customers. As used herein, the “Service(s)” refers to the applications, services, and websites (marketing and product) provided by LogMeIn. LogMeIn may, from time-to-time, introduce new products and services. To the extent that any new products and/or services affect this Privacy Policy, we will notify you as further described in Section 8 below.

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our practices, please contact us. If you are in the European Union, you may contact our Data Protection Officer through this same email address.

**Contents:**

1.  **Information We Collect and Receive**
2.  **How We Use the Information We Collect and Receive**
3.  **Analytics, Cookies and Other Web Site Technologies**
4.  **Information Sharing**
5.  **Communicating**
6.  **Data Location and Retention**
7.  **Your Rights and Choices**
8.  **Security**
9.  **International Data Transfers**
10.  **Children’s Privacy**
11.  **Changes to this Statement/Contact Us**

**1\. Information We Collect and Receive**

We collect several different types of information, including:

**Customer Account and Registration Data:** This includes information you provide to create your account with us or register for events, webinars, surveys, etc. and may include, first and last name, billing information, a password and a valid email address.

**Service Data (including Session and Usage data):** When you visit our websites and use our Services, we receive information either voluntarily entered by you or others (for example, schedules, attendee info, etc.), or passively logged by the website or Service itself, (for example, duration of session, use of webcams, connection information, etc.). We may also collect usage and log data about how the Services are accessed and used, including information about the device you are using to access the Services, IP addresses, location information, language settings, what operating system you are using, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data to help us support and improve upon the Services.

**Third Party Data:** We may receive information about you from other sources, including publicly available databases or from third parties from whom we have purchased data, and combine this data with information we already have about you. We may also receive information from other affiliated companies that are a part of our corporate group. This third-party data is obtained for our legitimate business interests and helps us to update, expand and analyze our records, identify new prospects for marketing, and provide products and services that may be of interest to you.

**Location Information:** We collect your location-based information for the purpose of providing and supporting the Service and for fraud prevention and security monitoring. If you wish to opt-out of the collection and use of your location information, you may do so by disabling location services on your mobile device.

**Device Information:** When you use our online and mobile Services, we may automatically collect information about the type of device you use, for example, the operating system version or the device identifier (or "UDID").

**2\. How We Use the Information We Collect and Receive**

LogMeIn may access and use the data we collect as necessary: (a) to provide and operate Services. (b) to address and respond to service, security, and customer support issues. (c) to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, unlawful, or technical issues. (d) as required by law. (e) to fulfill our contracts. (f) to improve and enhance the Services. and/or (g) to provide analysis or valuable information back to our customers and users.

Some specific examples of how we use the information:

*   Create and administer your account
*   Send you an order confirmation
*   Facilitate and improve the usage of the Services you have ordered
*   Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products
*   Send you product updates, marketing communication, and service information
*   Respond to customer inquiries and support requests
*   Conduct research and analysis
*   Display content based upon your interests
*   Analyze data, including through automated systems and machine learning to improve our Services and/or your experience
*   Provide you information about your use of the Services and benchmarks, insights and suggestions for improvements

LogMeIn also collects and stores meeting attendee information to fulfill our obligation to our customers and provide the Services. With their consent or under their instructions, we may also directly provide product and other LogMeIn related information to attendees. LogMeIn will retain your information, under a lawful basis, as long as your account with us is active, to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

If you wish to cancel your account or for us to stop providing you Services, or if we hold personal information about you and you want it to be removed from our database or de-activated, please contact us here.

**Grasshopper Users**  
Notwithstanding anything else in this Privacy Policy, if you provide Grasshopper access to the following types of your Google data, Grasshopper’s use of that data will be subject to the following restrictions: (i) Grasshopper will only use that access to read, write, modify, delete, or control Gmail message bodies (including attachments), metadata, headers, and settings to provide web email client functionality that allows users to compose, send, read, and/or process emails and will not transfer this Gmail data to others unless doing so is necessary to provide and improve these features, comply with applicable law, or as part of a merger, acquisition, or sale of assets. (ii) Grasshopper will not use this Gmail data for serving advertisements. and (iii) Grasshopper will not allow humans to read this data (i.e., by utilization of robust access controls, procedures, etc., inclusive of the principle of least privilege) unless we have your affirmative agreement for specific messages, doing so is necessary for security purposes such as investigating abuse, in response to requested support/troubleshooting, to comply with applicable law, or for Grasshopper’s internal operations and even then only when the data have been aggregated and anonymized.

**3\. Analytics, Cookies and Other Web Site Technologies**

LogMeIn continuously improves its websites and Services through the use of various third-party web analytics tools, which help LogMeIn understand how its visitors use its websites, desktop tools, and mobile applications, what they like and dislike, and where they may have run into problems which need to be addressed.

Geolocation and Other Data:

We may utilize precise Geolocation data but only if you specifically opt-in to or permit collection of that data in connection with a particular Service. We also use information such as IP addresses to determine the general geographic locations areas of our visitors. The web beacons used in conjunction with these web analytics tools may gather data such as what browser or operating system a person uses, as well as, domain names, MIME types, and what content, products and services are reviewed or downloaded when visiting or registering for Services at one of our websites or using one of our mobile applications.

Google Analytics and Adobe Marketing Cloud:

We use Google Analytics as described in “How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps.” You can prevent your data from being used by Google Analytics on websites by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on here. We also employ IP address masking, a technique used to truncate IP addresses collected by Google Analytics and store them in an abbreviated form to prevent them from being traced back to individual users. Portions of our website may also use Google Analytics for Display Advertisers including DoubleClick or Dynamic Remarketing which provide interest-based ads based on your visit to this or other websites. You can use Ads Settings to manage the Google ads you see and opt-out of interest-based ads. We also use Adobe Marketing Cloud as described here. You can opt-out of use of this information as described below.

Tracking Technologies:

LogMeIn and our partners use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track user traffic patterns and hold certain registration information. Other tracking technologies used are beacons, tags and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Services. If you wish to not have the information these technologies collect used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out here, or if located in the European Union, click here. The Help Menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. You can still review the website if you choose to set your browser to refuse all cookies. however, you must enable cookies to establish an account and to install the Services. To manage Flash Cookies, please click here.

Examples of Cookies We Use:

Cookie Type

Purpose

Description

Session Cookies

We use these cookies to operate our websites.

Some cookies are essential for the operation of LogMeIn websites. If a user chooses to disable these cookies, the user will not be able to access all of the content and features.

Preference Cookies

We use these cookies to remember your preferences.

When you register at a LogMeIn website, we use cookies to store unique, randomly assigned user IDs that we generate for administrative purposes. These cookies enable you to enter the LogMeIn sites without having to log on each time.

Advertising Cookies

These cookies are used to serve you with advertisements that may be relevant to you and your interests.

We use cookies to make advertising more engaging to users, as well as to assist in reporting on marketing program performance and analytics.

Security Cookies

These cookies are used for general security purposes and user authentication.

We use security cookies to authenticate users, prevent fraudulent use of login credentials, and protect user data from access by unauthorized parties.

**Mobile Analytics**

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our mobile software on your mobile device. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.  
Social Media: Our sites include social media features, such as Facebook, Google and Twitter “share” buttons. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. These services will also authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign-up form or provide feedback. Your interactions with these features are governed by the Privacy Policy of the third-party company providing them.

**4\. Information Sharing**

Ensuring your privacy is important to us. We do not share your personal information with third parties except as described in this Privacy Policy. We may share your personal information with: (a) third party service providers. (b) business partners. (c) affiliated companies within our corporate structure. and (d) as needed for legal purposes. Third-party service providers have access to personal information only as needed to perform their functions and they must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. These transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by appropriate transfer agreements such as the EU Model Clauses.

Examples of how we may share information with service providers include:

*   Fulfilling orders and providing the Services
*   Payment processing and fraud prevention
*   Providing customer support
*   Sending marketing communications
*   Conducting research and analysis
*   Providing cloud computing infrastructure

Examples of how we may disclose data for legal reasons include:

*   As part of a merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company where customer information will be one of the transferred assets.
*   As required by law, for example, to comply with a valid subpoena or other legal process. when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, or to protect your safety (or the safety of others). to investigate fraud. or to respond to a government request.

**5\. Communicating**

LogMeIn may need to communicate with you for a variety of different reasons, including:

*   Responding to your questions and requests. If you contact us with a problem or question, we will use your information to respond.
*   Sending you important transactional and/or administrative emails and messages about Services that you use. We may contact you to inform you about changes in our Services, our Service offerings, and important Service-related notices, such as billing, security and fraud notices. These emails and messages are considered a necessary part of the Services and you may not opt-out of them.
*   Sending emails about LogMeIn news or products that we think you’d like to hear about either from us or our business partners, in each case, under a legitimate business interest and/or based upon your request. If you are not interested in receiving these communications, you can always opt out of these types of messages at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of each communication or by following the instructions at Section 7 and/or Section 12 of this Privacy Policy.
*   Conducting surveys. We may use the information gathered in the surveys to enhance and personalize our products, Services, and websites.
*   Offering referral programs and incentives, which allow you to utilize email, text, or URL links that you can share with friends or colleagues.

**6\. Data Location and Retention**

We only retain a limited amount of personal data, under an appropriate and lawful basis, for as long as needed for the business purposes for which they were collected or as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. After that time frame, we delete or anonymize the data according to our data retention policies and/or procedures.

**7\. Your Rights and Choices**

Our customers can always review, update or change personal information from within their account or by contacting us. LogMeIn will also, when you request, provide you with information about the types of information we process about you and whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. You may have the right to a copy of your personal information in machine-readable format.

You can also ask about:

*   whether and why we have your personal information;
*   how we obtained your personal information;
*   what we have done with your personal information;
*   to whom we have communicated your personal information;
*   where your personal information has been stored, processed or transferred;
*   how long we will retain your personal information or how that retention period will be determined. and
*   the safeguards in place to protect your information when it is transferred to third parties or third countries.

Finally, you can ask us: (a) not to collect or use your personal information for certain purposes. (b) to update or delete your personal information. or (c) to provide your personal information to a third party.

To make any of these requests, please contact us at https://support.logmeininc.com/contactus which allows you to make a request online or through a phone call.

We may also collect information on behalf of our customers, to provide the Services, and we may not have a direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data is processed. If you are a customer or end-user of one of our customers, please contact them (as the data controller or legal equivalent) directly with any of these requests.

Depending on which laws apply to your personal information, we may only be able to fulfill some of the above requests for you. If you make a request and we have a justified lawful reason to maintain your information (e.g., legal and audit purposes), we will explain your legal rights, the reason we are maintaining such information and, if applicable, any recourse you may have.

We will respond to your request without undue delay, but in any event within thirty (30) days. We reserve the right to take reasonable steps to verify your identity prior to granting access or processing changes or corrections.

If you wish to no longer receive marketing communications from us, you can opt-out of marketing by clicking on the unsubscribe link on any marketing email you receive, or http://solutions.logmein.com/unsubscribe. Note that if you are a LastPass user, please visit https://lp.logmeininc.com/unsubscribe to opt-out.

You may also have the right to complain to a regulatory authority. If you have a question or complaint, we ask that you please contact us first. If you are in the EU and we are unable to resolve your complaint, you may complain to the Data Protection Authority in your home country.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.

**APEC Cross Border Privacy Rules System**

LogMeIn’s privacy practices, described in this Privacy Policy, comply with the APEC Cross Border Privacy Rules System. The APEC CBPR system provides a framework for organizations to ensure protection of personal information transferred among participating APEC economies. More information about the APEC framework can be found here.

**EU-U.S. and Swiss Privacy Shield**

LogMeIn has self-certified to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss Privacy Shield with respect to Customer Data. For more information, see our Privacy Shield Notice.

**8\. Security**

LogMeIn follows generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. However, no security measure is perfect. We recommend safeguarding your password, as it is one of the easiest ways you can manage the security of your own account – remember that if you lose control over your password, you may lose control over your personal information.

**9\. International Data Transfers**

LogMeIn is headquartered in the United States of America and maintains a global infrastructure. Information that we collect and maintain may be transferred to, or controlled and processed in, the United States and/or other countries around the world. Although these countries may have different data protection laws to the laws of your country, we will protect the privacy and security of personal information we collect in accordance with this Privacy Policy, regardless of where it is processed or stored. Where LogMeIn processes European Union personal information outside of the European Union in countries not declared to have adequate protections, it does so in compliance with Chapter 5 of the GDPR (e.g., under the E.U.-US and Swiss Privacy Shield Framework(s) and/or Standard Contractual Clauses) and applicable law.

To learn more about the locations where LogMeIn may process your personal information through its affiliated companies or third-party Sub-processors (when LogMeIn acts as a data processor, service provider, and/or the applicable legal equivalent), please visit the Product Resources section of the LogMeIn Trust &. Privacy Center.

**10\. California Privacy Rights**

_California Consumer Privacy Act_

Additionally, the California Consumer Privacy Act, or CCPA, which takes effect on January 1, 2020, is intended to provide California residents with expanded rights to access, delete and control their personal information. Any terms defined in the CCPA have the same meaning when used in this Privacy Policy.

For personal information collected by us during the preceding twelve (12) months that is not otherwise subject to an exception, California residents have the right to access and delete their personal information. We will not discriminate against those who exercise their rights. Specifically, if you exercise your rights, we will not deny you access to our Services, charge you different prices for Services or provide you a different level or quality of Services.

The CCPA additionally requires businesses to provide or make available certain disclosures in the event a party sells your personal information to third parties, however because LogMeIn does not receive any personal information as consideration for any Services or other items provided or performed by LogMeIn, these disclosures do not apply. LogMeIn does not collect, retain, share or use any personal information except as necessary for a business purpose pursuant to a written contract (i.e., to provide and operate the Services) and subject to the restrictions specified in Section 1798.140 (v) of the CCPA. Additionally, LogMeIn refrains from taking any action that would cause any transfers of personal information that qualify as "selling personal information" under the CCPA or other similar applicable privacy laws.

California residents may exercise the rights specified in this Privacy Policy or request information from us regarding whether we share certain categories of your personal information with third parties by contacting privacy@logmein.com.

_California Shine the Light_

Residents of the State of California, under California Civil Code § 1798.83, have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third parties to which the company has disclosed personal information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, the law provides that if the company has a privacy policy that gives either an opt-out or opt-in choice for use of your personal information by third parties (such as advertisers) for marketing purposes, the company may instead provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options.

LogMeIn qualifies for the alternative option. We have a comprehensive privacy statement and provide you with details on how you may either opt-out or opt-in to the use of your personal information by third parties for direct marketing purposes. Therefore, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of the third parties that received your personal information for marketing purposes during the preceding year.

**11\. Children’s Privacy**

LogMeIn’s webpages are intended for general audiences – we do not seek through this site to gather personal data from or about persons that are sixteen (16) years of age or younger. If you inform us or we otherwise become aware that we have unintentionally received personal information from an individual under the age of sixteen (16), we will delete this information from our records.

**12\. Changes to this Statement/Contact Us**

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes that have a substantive and adverse impact on your privacy, we will provide notice on this website and notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) for your approval prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

If you have any other questions about this policy please contact LogMeIn Privacy Team, or call +1 805 690 6400 or write to us via postal mail at: LogMeIn, 320 Summer Street, Boston, MA 02210. To reach our Global Customer Support department, you may contact us here.
